RYAN INGERSOLL

ingytrader.com

24385 Wilderness Oak #8306--San Antonio, TX 78258—ingytrader@gmail.com--cell#(210) 912-4339

Financial Engineer and Full Stack Web Developer

I own the unique double threat of being a full-stack, web developer coupled with the savvy of a veteran derivatives trader of the last two decades. The value I deliver lies in my ability to develop and code proprietary quantitative strategies as well as bridge the communication gaps which occur between trading desks and application developers for investment banks, prop firms or hedge funds.

Full Stack Web Developer (LAMP +J)
Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP and Python
JavaScript, JQuery and Laravel MVC framework
HTML/CSS and Twitter Bootstrap

Professional Experience

Director of Investment Research and Technology (October 2013 to Present) SRI Diversified Capital, LLC. San Antonio, TX.

Commodity Futures Trader - Independent (2006 to 2013) Chicago, IL Summer Analyst -Goldman Sachs (summer 2006) New York City, NY Equity HFT-Independent (1999 to 2006) San Antonio, TX Branch Manager Paulson Investment Co. (1996 to 1999) Investment Representative George E. Dullnig and Co. (1994 to 1996)

I am currently enrolled in **Codeup's** immersive 12-week Web Developer/Programming bootcamp for working professionals (Graduation Nov. 5th 2014). This is an intense program to develop skills with the LAMP +J stack: Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP and client-side JavaScript using the Laravel framework and jQuery. The curriculum goes way beyond the parameters of traditional computer science degrees through **interaction with the local tech community to create new business web applications** via the capstone project. In this way, Codeup graduates become seasoned "plug and play" problem solvers who **bring value added solutions to solve company specific issues.**

Achievements and Leadership

- As the lead investment and technology analyst for SRI Diversified Capital, I have consulted on multiple drilling projects within the Eagle Ford Shale development. One of my primary responsibilities is to create unique risk management solutions for the energy sector. This eventually led to an extension of profit opportunities of insurance beyond gap coverage of liabilities. Specifically I was able to draw on my expertise in risk transfer and distribution through the futures markets to engineer the framework of a new exchange traded derivatives platform for the reinsurance industry known as the ILF index.
- Having traded across the entire spectrum of the capital markets, IMHO The Russell 2000 Index futures (symbol #TF) offer the best combination of volatility, liquidity and low trading costs available. It is no coincidence then my primary strategy is a long/short option strategy focused around monthly expiration cycles of the #TF front month contract. To a lesser extent, I deployed capital around the WTI Crude futures (symbol CL). This was a volatility based system taking its entry and exits from my proprietary blend of the S&P VIX and the crude oil VIX. When the opportunities were right, I took less frequent positions against wheat, corn, soybeans, copper, 10 year Treasuries, S&P 500, Nasdaq and the Dow Jones. My option strategies combined put and call spreads, butterflies, strip, strap, strangles, and calendar spreads. Options consistently gave added flexibility to my directional trading as well as valuable risk management to my overall core positions.
- Chosen by Goldman Sachs for the Summer Analyst Program was the direct result of graduating from Kent State's prestigious master's program in Financial Engineering. My primary team assignments were to manage risk through bundling single name issuances of corporate debt within the Bank's inventory for modeling prices of offsetting CDS positions critical to the structured product trading desk.
- The opportunity to open a new regional branch of Paulson Investment Co in San Antonio, TX was a rare chance for a young
 professional to gain valuable management experience. I obtained the Series 7, 24 and 63 licenses which gave me
 authority to supervise the growth and compliance of over 300 new accounts, with assets under management of over \$50
 million.

EDUCATION

Codeup, San Antonio, TX 2014
M.S. Financial Engineering, Kent State University, Kent, OH, 2006
M.B.A. Finance, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX, 2005
B.B.A. Marketing, Texas A&M University, College Station, TX, 1994
Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Program completed levels 1 and II